There's literally no human to click the consent button.
So what was the agent actually succeeding at?
Our criteria had assumed
that OAuth would happen successfully because they were outcome oriented.
And so it was only looking at what the plausible outcome of the agent,
having actually interacted with the service that was doing OAuth
would have looked like, and the agent knew enough about the service to
plausibly hallucinate.
We run a lot of evals.
We've had a lot of pain running evils,
and we've had a lot of learnings from those emails.
So very happy to talk about anything that I chat about here
on these slides afterwards or at any point.
Also, all credit to Claude for the design of the slides.
I'm really bad designer, so the reason these look anything remotely too nice
is because of Claude.
Also, I know Simon said time for questions at the end.
We will leave some time.
If you do have any questions throughout the entire presentation,
please feel free to stick your hand up. Interrupt me.
Happy to kind of take those as we go along. Cool.
So basically what we've realized is that a lot of the coding benchmarks
that we got out there sweet bench, terminal, bench,
the leaderboards, all of those kind of things,
they're great, but they're a single number.
And there are a number that we've sort of stopped trusting a little bit
because of all of the kind of other impacts to that number.
So really what this talk is about is really trying
to get at what those numbers
actually are, measuring the ways that we can start
to decompose that into signals that we can actually trust,
and also the knowledge that we've learned that the numbers
aren't really what we expect them to be,
and that if we were just blindly optimizing
for the benchmark number for just benchmarking,
it's not going to get us the the results that we wanted to their there are three
main traps that we kind of saw that we'll go through in sequence.
I think personally I think they show up everywhere
else, Arun, including at the labs.
And it's not that evils are broken.
I really don't want to, Glenn, that we run far too many of them to be saying
evals are broken, but it's more so that figuring out how to evaluate
AI agents, that itself is a discipline.
I don't think we figure that out yet as a research community.
And so if we just treat it as cool, just run an eval,
then you're going to be led down the wrong path.
You actually need to
think about what it is, what signal you are that you're measuring.
So this is some numbers just from a run that we did last week.
This is for the Kimmy launch recently.
So Kimmy 2.5 and 2.6.
We ran this on Kimmy CLE backed by Kimmy platform.
So the official committee platform
same scenario same harmonies same eval orchestrator exact same everything.
And we were seeing radically different failure rates about 18 times
higher failure rate for 2.6 than we saw for 2.5.
This was kind of unexpected since, you know,
we think that 2.6 should be a better model, should be a better model.
This would be a regression.
This would be something bad that can be a chip
because it's showing up over pretty wide diversity of evils.
We run over 500 different skills and over 2000
different scenarios, kind of for benchmark that we do on new model releases.
So this would be at that point where like, okay, what's going on here.
When we started to dig into it.
It wasn't Kimmy was us, and it was specifically Daytona.
That's where the container platform that we end up running our evals on,
and it turned out, can be 2.6.
For whatever reason, when running, the Kimmy CLI started using up a lot more
a lot more memory on the box.
And so we had to bump the memory resources on the box.
We are kind of pretty consistently at a 3% rate,
and we weren't capturing that and being able to debug that easily, but also
that was showing up as failures, because the way that we had constructor
eval harness was not something that had to deal with this.
So some of you had a headline number of shoots.
Something is looking a lot worse than look before for
when we have kind of a strong prior that, hey, this should be a better model.
It is a model bump we'd expect the labs to be doing,
doing their due diligence and making sure that these are all better.
So what I would claim is that every eval lives somewhere between
kind of this axis of synthetic versus kind of real project, and there's kind of
trade offs that you're making across all of these, across this entire axis.
Synthetic. Those are the super easy ones.
Like they're controlled, they're cheap, they're repeatable.
You've got kind of a known state.
You've got a known scenario, you've got a known fixture.
It's pretty easy to do.
The real ones are the ones that are a little bit more difficult
because you're trying to do evil's over if something that changes in time.
So if you're modeling evals over a repo over a project,
that project is going to accrue different patterns,
different architecture, different features over time.
And so you can't just run the same eval scenario that you had before on the repo
under an a new timestamp, because, hey, the entire repo has changed. So
we think the real the real project evolves.
They have a lot of value.
They give you actual indication on what you, as a software engineer feel when
using a coding agent in your repo day to day,
but it is a much harder state space to be modeling and a much harder
to run versus the synthetic one, which might give you
a bit of a fuzzier signal, but give you cheaper.
You can run it more repeatedly.
Think unit test versus integration or into end test ones.
Expensive but stronger, signal ones cheaper but weaker signal.
Where do you kind of make the trade offs between the two?
So the first kind of pillar that I wanted to talk
about is what we've started to call kind of the outcome trap.
It's kind of the easy thing to be measuring.
It's did the agent produce the correct code?
Did the test pass? If you're doing something that's kind of sweet,
sweet bench kind of informed, did the task complete?
Did it do something?
What we realized is that it's kind of like
that's a necessary condition, but it's not the sufficient condition.
But we actually care about for a large number of things, particularly
skills is not what the agent did, but how the agent did it.
It's the workflow that it followed. Did it read your security policy?
Did it apply that?
Did it make sure all your endpoints have the proper endpoint protection
to go check linear
and update
the linear ticket in order to make sure that it tracked its work to file a PR?
Did it do all of that stuff?
And that's the stuff that we're seeing is encoded within skills.
A lot of skills are workflows and workflow oriented in terms of a sequence of steps
that you're meant to do, not.
Your output code must look exactly like this.
So this can mean
that the model can take shortcuts that happen to work on this scenario,
but won't necessarily generalize across other scenarios
that are kind of out of what this scenario is evaluating.
So what I would say
is that if you're only going to measure kind of the final outcome,
all of those ways of either
guessing the correct answer or skipping a couple of steps
or kind of jumping to the conclusion that looks like real success.
And so you might ship
a skill that you think is working, but it's actually not being loaded.
It's not being used, it's
not guiding the agent down the correct path
because it just happens to be getting there.
That is a separate question.
Also to understand in terms of
if it's doing, if it is completing the task
without your skill, is it actually valuable?
That's in a different talk though.
So for this one, this is one specific eval case that we had that was actually run
by one of our researchers internally at T-cell.
And it showed phenomenal improvements, 6.25 x improvements from kind of
the baseline case of no context to the experimental case of with context.
When we're kind of passing in the skill, it was pretty much the highest one
that we'd ever seen repeated, and we started to dig into it.
I mean, like, cool. What is so awesome about the skill?
We are first looking at the skill content
and trying to understand like, hey, is this skill content actually good?
Is there something that we can learn or generalize from that?
And then we started looking at the trajectories,
and then we started looking at the scenario on the output.
It turns out that the first step in this skill is OAuth.
So you've got an OAuth against a external service.
And then you can go follow the sequence of steps within that skill.
We don't support within our sandboxes.
We don't have that mechanism at the moment to be allowing your agents or whatever
coding agent to go off against a service that you haven't provided an API key
or another mechanism to do credential or to do authentication with.
There's literally no human to click the consent button.
So what was the agent actually succeeding at?
Our criteria had assumed
that OAuth would happen successfully because they were outcome oriented.
And so it was only looking at what the plausible outcome of the agent,
having actually interacted with the service that was doing OAuth
would have looked like, and the agent knew enough
about the service to plausibly hallucinate.
Given the context of the skill,
what an appropriate outcome would actually look like.
So we started having to realize, like, hey,
we need to start looking at trajectories.
And so not just this, but a bunch of other kind of scenarios and findings
we've had, and also the realization that, hey,
workflows are actually what people are doing.
That's really where we started
to invest more heavily in terms of kind of doing criteria
that aren't just tightly coupled to the actual outcome,
but criteria that are also coupled to the trajectory.
So being able to look at both of those dimensions
so you can actually evaluate
what kind of impact your skill has rather than just the outcome of that skill.
This is a fun gotcha.
But it's also kind of one that we think is more around
how we think about kind of framing evals and framing the approach
rather than something that we're going to have continuously
now that we're looking at kind of trajectories.
Yeah, cool.
We solved that one.
We're going to be able to kind of support this moving forward.
The one that I think we start to get into a little bit more trouble
is probably too far, but is a little bit more difficult, is also looking at judges.
And so LLM is a judge. We love it.
It's great being able to define rubrics and being able to have a bunch of llms
go assess the quality of either
a trajectory or an outcome based off that, that it makes our lives
a lot easier rather than going in hand grading a bunch of stuff.
But this does raise a problem.
One of the things that we started to notice is, yes, that there is a strong
there's kind of been some reports, some results reported in the literature
around self biasing of models in terms of hey, you have a sonnet model.
Great, a sonnet solution.
It's going to give it a higher score than if it's creating a GPT solution.
What we also started see is that those apply across model families as well.
So sonnet has a preference for GLM five one for whatever reason.
That is much higher than the preference
that GPT five five shows for GLM five one solutions.
So it's not just
you've got to make sure that you aren't just comparing within the model family.
You've also got to understand what the cross model family kind of bias is.
And so that is one of the other kind of issues with this judging bit
that we started to see.
And so this actually comes from one of the results at Simon
shared on the blog, I believe yesterday or today, very recently
that was looking at kind of or soon tomorrow.
Okay.
This will be shared tomorrow.
That is looking at exactly this.
So we had a bunch of scenarios.
We thought they showed phenomenal.
Very interesting results for GPT five five was actually worse
than GPT five three when we were being evaluating against one set of judges.
Then we started to investigate
and swapped in another set of judges and then another set of judges.
And then we started to see, okay, cool.
This is really what a case is of this.
It's a case of where there is some bias within a model family
towards a certain kind of solution or a certain set of solution.
So it wasn't kind of like catastrophic.
We're not going from 0 to 70 5 or 70 5 to 100 or something along those lines.
But it does kind of shift directionally the rankings
and shift kind of the results that you can for from that.
We want to mitigate this, though, because we use it a lot.
As I mentioned, we are big on our own as it judges, and we do think that this is
something you can mitigate, though, by putting in place enough checks.
Functionally. What we do is we run a lot of benchmarks.
We really try to understand the biases that each of these families will have
for either,
as I said, other models within that family or other models across families.
We also are building rubrics
because we find that those help reduce the inherent variance within Nivel.
Once you've got kind of like an artifact.
And yes, that artifact can be lemmas or LM generated,
but that helps ground the kind of scores and around the kind of results
that you're getting.
And we also start to averaging across different model families.
Like as with so many things, rather than just trying to get the one cherry
picked result, that is great.
Run out a bunch of times, do the average it starts to work out.
I think the real
big learning for us around this was it's not just averaging across the solutions.
That was something that we've been doing from the start
with recognition of the variance,
particularly in a non-deterministic setting with an environment in code
and all the kind of stuff that can go wrong. There it was.
We were always doing that kind of like run multiple solutions.
It was the oh, we also need to run multiple judges
and also need to do apply that same kind of principle
and that same kind of rigor to both sides of that equation.
Finally, scale.
So this is more on the infrastructure side and this is
more on the weird stuff happens when you are running at scale.
And that basically just comes down to any distributed service.
So super easy, super trivial when we're running kind of even
500 scenarios on a user's laptop, when someone on the research team
is there to click the button and it goes running locally,
that's a pretty good setting. We know locked up to go off.
We know the laptop is going to be connected to our office Wi-Fi.
It's strong and stable, all those kind of things.
That's pretty repeatable.
When we started to run these kind of 20,000 times, 30,000
times, 40,000 times across Daytona, across AWS,
across all of our different infrastructure providers.
And we then need to be kind of
considering load balancing across anthropic, across bedrock, across vertex.
Because of the scale eval runs are we start to see that hey misconfiguration.
Hey, those out of memory resource limits that I was talking about before
actually start to not just cause failures, but start to cause
differences in the scores that we're seeing anthropic or other.
Yeah.
So things that kind of broke at this scale, anthropic is the next slide.
Sorry. Things that work at the scale.
These are kind of
like the super concrete stuff that is very top of my mind at the moment.
There have been other issues in the past.
One is still Docker layers.
This is the chronic issue in terms of versioning of software.
I can't count the number of times that I've had the different version of Docker
running in public, or running on our cloud,
versus running locally on my machine.
This is all stuff that as you mature, you build the processes and the checks
and all that kind of stuff in place, but it's also stuff that makes versioning
and keeping track of the metadata specifically so important.
Because the number of times we've had, hey, cool, we've had a regression.
Oh no. Clod code just changed.
That is also been higher
than I would care to admit in terms of concurrent sandbox accounting.
Cool.
This is a specific work with Daytona where it will tell us, hey,
the sandbox is shutting down or shutting down.
It will act that request that we've made, but the sandbox itself
will then take a little bit longer to shut down,
and we immediately go, cool, okay, we got an sandboxes down.
Let's go spend another one up. No. Now we've got two sandboxes.
When we were expecting one sandbox to be running,
and we've used up all of our resource limits.
Another one in terms of zero second hangs, we've had a couple of things
that just hang like, just don't work.
Is that Daytona?
Is that the CLI?
Is that the underlying model
never been a big enough issue to kind of go investigate, but
been enough that we kind of need to go kick those boxes every once in a while.
So there's kind of a retry and a refresh loop
that is needed there in order to make sure that you're
kind of not just wasting time and wasting compute.
And then in terms of pod errors. Yeah.
BC basically this concept of like a bunch of tasks failing
when we kind of have super strict resource requirements because again,
non-deterministic agents that are writing code, importing dependencies,
loading up your system memory by doing really, really big VMs
or really, really big node modules and then importing everything.
And these again, often show up as failures because your solution didn't
complete it, didn't write out or it didn't get fully to the end, but they're not.
Their resource issues in the model
would have actually finished had it been given the opportunity to do so.
This is the anthropic slide that I was thinking of.
So this is from results back in Ethiopia published back in February,
that are basically what we saw just a couple of months later
because they're, as usual, leading the field.
And so it's very similar to that kind of concept.
It's like cool.
You've got a bunch of different resource configurations that you can give to a,
to an environment that are using to run terminal bench in their case.
And just by changing the amounts of resources that you're giving
to that environment, you actually affect the model performance
and therefore you affect the reward signal that you can get from that performance
in an VR setting.
And so that's super important because this is now
something that is not related to your model, not related to your agent
harness, but is related to something external to that.
So now you're not just trying to say, hey, I'm optimizing my model.
It's cool. Now I'm accidentally optimizing my model.
Given the resource constraints that I've used
for the environments that I'm running my emails in,
that is a much fuzzier signal than kind of you would hope it to be.
So what I would claim kind of overall
is that if you got kind of slow evals, slow comprehensive evals,
kind of the ones on the left, the really nice ones like those are great,
but they're not actually something that you can really effectively learn from.
These might be the real world projects that have time drift,
that you kind of spinning up an entire ecosystem,
like an entire dev ecosystem on a box, so that you give the agent
the most representative
eval scenario, eval environment possible, but then you've got really hard
kind of constraints in terms of getting that reward signal back
when the evil takes 24 hours to run, because it's complicated and difficult.
On the other side, you've got the really narrow ones.
These are the synthetic ones that we talked about.
Those
give you a cheaper, fuzzier reward signal, but they give it to you much quicker.
And so where do you want to sit kind of along that line, along that axis.
In terms of what is more valuable, is it to get something that is a fuzzier
approximation of reality, but quicker, so that you can
then optimize and train on that?
Or does it get a better representation of reality?
But it's slower.
And so yes, you get better data, but it takes you longer to run
kind of a reinforcement
learning loop or to optimize your context or anything along those lines.
And so I think for me sitting on this team, really
the most interesting perspective is that
and I come from a software engineering background for context,
is that evil infrastructure,
like these annoying bits of dealing with out of memory,
these annoying bits of looking at networking,
these annoying bits of figuring out how it works.
That's just not software engineering, platform investment.
That's like research investment.
That is the thing that we need to do in order to do research,
because otherwise we are getting noisy signal and noisy data, and that affects
the quality of the research that we ought to do.
And so it's not kind of this disjoint between cool.
The research investment is just
on the evil design or just on the criteria or just on the environments.
No, the research investment is just as much
on the underlying infrastructure, because all of this is connected
and only by kind of making sure one is solid, making sure that pieces are
solid, can you actually get the insights that you want?
So there's another kind of learning from this.
And that is really around decomposition.
So for each of those three kind of traps there's three issues
that I mentioned earlier.
Outcome judge scale.
There's a decomposition element to it as well.
So in terms of the outcome, the decomposition is going from
just looking at the outcome to looking at each step that the agent takes
to be more effectively able to measure the thing that you actually care about.
In some cases, it's just the how you don't care about how.
Sorry. It's just the what. It's not. You don't care about how you got there.
In other cases, you don't care about the what's and it's just the how.
And so you just want to look at that often it's both for the judge problem.
We can decompose that into making sure that the judge's checking small
verifiable claims rather than hey, is quality good?
Or hey, is this code correct?
Or hey, is this code secure?
The more work that you do in terms of defining that rubric
at a sufficient granularity, the more kind of the more agreement
that you will see across different judges in different judging families.
Yeah, opus four seven is great because you can give it a shitty prompt
and it will figure something out.
But if you're able to kind of break that down and decompose it,
you're going to get a lot more reliability out of it.
And then on the scale, well, we want to be able to decompose something
that we can run kind of fast and narrow for getting some of that signal.
But we also want to keep that opportunity for being able to run that super slow.
Shouldn't say super slow slow.
It's like a day for Take That, the opportunity for running that
comprehensive one, for the opportunities where it drives us, the value.
So it's really being able to understand the domain that we are optimizing against
enough that we can pick
and choose which signals are valuable, at which point in that cycle.
I would much rather run 100 unit tests than I would one end to end test.
If I can get 95% of the confidence from the unit testing, then I would be
from the end to end testing.
So this is kind of where I'm getting to in terms of
like what that bigger point is, and it's that we don't really know
how to properly evaluate these
because there are so many different moving parts of this system.
We've gone from a world where the original evaluations on an LLM
were give it some text and get some text back.
And that's all you're evaluating now we've got environments.
Now we've got agent harnesses, now we've got external dependencies.
Now we've got the file system.
Like there's so many things that could go wrong in this entire domain
that are all going to have an impact on it.
And so how do we then start to think through as kind of a community in terms
of figuring out which bits of that are important
and how we were able to then evaluate and report on that,
because it doesn't matter to me if they tell me, Claude, code with opus
47 got score whatever on Terminal bench.
If I don't know the closest cloud code version that that score got that
that score was run with, because it has shown that, hey,
cloud code changes the performance or the resource configuration
because I might be running on a smaller box and hey,
it can't actually write as much code.
So the last thing that I
kind of want to say is really what I've tried to kind of line here
is basically having an honest, honest mental model of what your evals are
in, aren't telling you like, yes, having a single number, that's great.
It gives you something to optimize against.
And if that's what you need to kind of report out, then fine.
I'm not against having a single number.
We do need to do some aggregation.
We can't just say everything is multiple numbers
or everything needs to be
kind of broken down into smaller parts, but be honest, kind of about what
those individual bits are
and if it is something that is going to bite you,
or if it is something where you're measuring
kind of the fuzzy approximation
because you're only looking at outcome and not the process, then yeah, that's fair.
You don't need to measure everything, but be aware of where those blind spots
are because you're a trust or evals a lot more when you're able to caveat them
with kind of the incorrect bits or the parts that you don't know and be,
then hopefully be building in a way that you can start to mitigate that.
Moving on. So that's pretty much it.
I think Simon has a fun throwing mic for questions.
Yeah.
Who's got a question
for all and who's going to catch me?
What if you're only good at one of those things.
So you mentioned that you need to run your ball fast.
What kind of tools are your favorite in this situation?
So I talked a lot about Daytona
and our frustrations with Daytona, but I love Daytona for that reason.
So basically we have invested a fair amount
in our own custom eval orchestrator, but it is all running on Daytona
as kind of our compute platform because of kind of subsecond startup times.
And when we want to spin up a whole bunch of eval containers, that really helps.
We haven't invested significantly in terms of like actually tuning
the evil environments themselves, because we'd rather paralyze out across
environments and cross scenarios than kind of speeding up any single run.
So I think our stack kind of biases a little bit towards
do a lot of things in parallel, rather than do any specific things super fast.
The implication of that, though, is that we then try to make rival scenarios
kind of as small as possible in order to get the signal that we want,
rather than having kind of
a bigger, complex scenario that might be measuring multiple things
that take a longer time, but then we can at least run them in parallel
on. Potentially controversial question
do you really need to evaluate for processes, or can you elaborate that
by using a large range of or representative data
that's been designed to trigger
processes?
Possibly.
So sorry.
The reason I'm hesitating there is just kind of thinking through
what how for some of the failure cases that we've seen where
we've needed to reach for the trajectory, if we would have been able
to construct a scenario or construct an outcome that would have triggered.
That may be, I think you can probably artificially construction
of scenarios that would cause a failure for any single step of the process.
But the fact that it is taking me
struggling a little bit to kind of think through what that process would look like
makes me want to reach for kind of like looking at the directory itself.
It kind of, in my mind, fits a bit more naturally in terms of like,
hey, you're asking the model,
you're asking the agent to go do a sequence of steps,
go look at whether it did the sequence of steps, not whether
you can create the scenario to have the outcome.
That would then imply it had the sequence of steps associated with it.
So I think it's possible.
I don't know if it's easier though.
Yeah.
I'm going to ask a actually I want to there's really no time for more questions.
I will take one more question, because I'll ask John to come up just to
just set up.
And after a while that happens, we'll take the first.
Further. I'm
sorry about.
I didn't want to get in the way of that.
In terms of what you said,
you've got a quick set of just.
How many.
People do you want to have and how long did it take?
How quick is great.
Yeah.
So any single scenario will take between 10 and 15 minutes.
And then we try to parallelize across that as much as we want
or as much as we can.
So kind of like our benchmark suites for any new model is
we've got 500 skills that we think are fairly represented, sample
of a bunch of different skills out there.
And then those decompose into.
Five.
That would mean different scenarios.
And so that will be kind of the set that we run over new models.
So from clock time on that is an hour because we don't kind of
do it entirely in parallel or just we don't feel the need to an hour.
It's a question of time for us to turn around.
We have explored doing a regression testing on kind of our product on PRS.
Didn't end up going for that,
because that ended up being about 15 minutes and that was felt.
It was too long, but we have looked more seriously.
I just kind of doing that on a nightly basis, because then it can be
kind of like the full suite for an hour overnight, being able to set that.
So not quite unit test time.
We would love to be able
to get down to unit test human the loop time, but enough that it's
PR review time, which is kind of the metric that we turn off for.
Thank you very much.
Please give it up for all.